### Muhammad Mahdi Hasan

Cell: +880 13 076 076 35

Portfolio : <a href="https://mahdisaikat.github.io/portfolio/">https://mahdisaikat.github.io/portfolio/</a>
Linkedin : <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahdisaikat/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahdisaikat/</a>

Github: <a href="https://github.com/mahdisaikat">https://github.com/mahdisaikat</a>
E-mail: <a href="mahdi.saikat@gmail.com">mahdi.saikat@gmail.com</a>

Address: Level-8, Asiatic Shopping Mall, Konapara Main

Road, Jatrabari, Dhaka - 1362.

## Career Objective

Adaptable professional with more than 2 years of experience and with the ability to follow established procedures and work under little or no supervision. Pursuing a new position where I can grow my skills more efficiently for the betterment of my career and the company.

# Professional Experience

#### Tiyasha Software | Bengaluru, Karnataka 560060, India.

Lead Software Engineer, (Remote) Feb 2021 – present

- Perform R&D on assigned project.
- Analysis software requirements & plan accordingly.
- Collect client's requirements & attend schedule meeting to discuss about their project and take their feedback.
- Design, build and maintain high performance, reusable and reliable code.
- Identify and correct bottlenecks and fix bugs.

#### Field Booster Ltd. | Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka 1229, Dhaka

**Software Engineer,** Jun 2020 – present

- Analysis & design project architecture
- Collect & analysis clients requirements.
- Design and build advance application for Web platform.

#### Creative Software Ltd. | Multiplan Center, New Elephant Road, Dhaka

Web Developer, Jul 2018 – May 2020

 Wrote highly maintainable, solid code to develop Laravel software for new projects, developed & modified code in existing projects according to requirements and also implemented API to merge different APPs with Laravel projects.

#### Dhaka Center NIC IT Ltd. | Uttara, Dhaka

Intern, Oct 2017 – Feb 2018

• Developed a project on Human Resource Management Software in ASP.net which can fulfil client's basic requirements.

**Skills** 

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, ASP.net, PHP, MySQL, Laravel, Lumen, Java, React (Learning).

Education

International University of Business Agriculture & Technology | Uttara, Dhaka

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering | December 2017

**Hobbies** 

Traveling  $\mid$  Playing games  $\mid$  Watching movies  $\mid$  Listening music  $\mid$  Gossiping with friends & family